Register of the Library of Social History Collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Fourth International Series, 1894-1991 (Box 1-199)
  - United States
    - Communist Party (Box 146)
      - Pamphlets
        - The American Legion and the Communists Discuss Democracy; Earl Browder, Concerted Action or Isolation; Earl Browder, The Democratic Front; Earl Browder, Social and National Security; Earl Browder, Study Guide and Outline for The People's Front; Earl Browder and Bill Lawrence, Next Steps to Win the War in Spain; Chen Lin, China's Fight for National Liberation; Mary Collins, Democracy in Danger; Mary Collins, The Fight for Recovery; Communist Election Platform 1938; The Constitution and By-laws of the Communist Party of the United States of America; Georgi Dimitrov, The Guarantee of Victory; Harry Gannes, The Munich Betrayal; Simon W. Gersimpsky, A Comrade Looks at the 1938 Election Campaign; Clarence A. Hathaway, Collective Security; Milton Howard, This Fourth of July; Mikhail Kalinin, World Peace or War?; A. B. Magil, The People's Message to Congress; Alan Max, May Day 1938; Resolutions of the Tenth Convention of the Communist Party, U.S.A. (Box-folder 147: 3)
        - Israel Amter, May Day 1939; Israel Amter, The Truth about Finland; Earl Browder, America and the Second Imperialist War; Earl Browder, The Economics of Communism; Earl Browder, The 1940 Elections; Earl Browder, Socialism, War, and America; Earl Browder, Theory as a Guide to Action; Earl Browder, Whose War Is It?; Georgi Dimitrov, The War and the Working Class; J. Fields, Behind the War Headlines; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Debs, Haywood, Ruthenberg; William Z. Foster, Your Questions Answered; Rob Fowler Hall, This Fourth of July; Roy Hudson, True Americans; Adam Lapin, The Un-American Dies Committee; M. J. Olgin; A. B. Magil, The Real Father Coughlin; D. Manuil'skii, The World Communist Movement; V. M. Molotov, The Meaning of the Soviet-German Non-Aggression Pact; Joseph North, Why Spain Can Win; Lowell Wakefield, Hitler's Spy Plot in the U.S.A. (Box-folder 147: 4)
        - Earl Browder, An American Foreign Policy for Peace; Earl Browder Takes His Case to the People; Earl Browder Talks to the Senators; Earl Browder, Internationalism, and Results of the 1940 Election; Earl Browder, The Jewish People and the War; Earl Browder, The People against the War Makers; Earl Browder, The People's Road to Peace; Earl Browder, "To the People Will Belong the Victory"; Louis F. Budenz, May Day 1940; Louis F. Budenz, Save Your Union!; Peter V. Cacchione, Gli italo-americani e la guerra; Georgi Dimitrov, The Struggle against the Imperialist War; Election Platform of the Communist Party 1940; Ernst Fischer, Is This a War for Freedom?; William Z. Foster, Capitalism, Socialism, and the War; William Z. Foster, Roosevelt Heads for War; William Z. Foster, The United States and the Soviet Union; William Z. Foster, The War Crisis; V. J. Jerome, Intellectuals and the War; V. J. Jerome, Social-Democracy and the War; André Marty, Who Betrayed France?; V. M. Molotov, Soviet Foreign Policy; V. M. Molotov, Soviet Foreign Relations; Gaston Richard, The Trial of the Communist Deputies in France; John Henry Williams, A Negro Looks at War (Box-folder 147: 5)
        - Israel Amter, May Day 1941; Earl Browder, Communism and Culture; Earl Browder, The Communist Party of the U.S.A.; Earl Browder Says; Earl Browder, The Way Out of the Imperialist War; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Earl Browder, the Man from Kansas; William Z. Foster, Communism versus Fascism; William Z. Foster, Defend America by Smashing Hitlerism; William Z. Foster, Socialism; William Z. Foster and Robert Minor, The Fight against Hitlerism; Roy Hudson, The Growth of the Trade Unions; Roy Hudson, Trends in the Labor Movement; Grace Hutchins, Japan Wars on the U.S.A.; André Marty, The Epic of the Black Sea Revolt; André Marty, How France Was Betrayed; Robert Minor, Free Earl Browder!; Robert Minor, One War to Defeat Hitler; Robert Minor et al., The Path of Browder and Foster; Wilhelm Pieck, International Solidarity; Mike Quin, The Enemy Within; The Red Army; Peter Wieden, New Aspects of Imperialism (Box-folder 148: 1)
        - .James S. Allen, The Crisis in India; Attack Hitler Now!; Earl Browder, Production for Victory; Earl Browder, Victory Must Be Won; Peter V. Cacchione, Public Speaking; Joseph Clark, Men of Liberty; Ernst Fischer, What Is Socialism?; William Z. Foster, From Defense to Attack; William Z. Foster, Labor and the War; William z. Foster, Smash Hitler's Spring Offensive Now!; William Z. Foster, Steel Workers and the War; William Z. Foster, The U.S.A. and the U.S.S.R.; Roy Hudson, Two Questions on Winning the War; Jürgen Kuczynski and M. Witt, The Economics of Barbarism; Elizabeth Lawson, Thaddeus Stevens; Robert Minor, The Year of Great Decision, 1942; Joseph North, Washington and Lincoln; K. Osipov, The Seven Years' War; William H. Patterson, Sikeston (Box-folder 148: 2)
        - Earl Browder, The Future of the Anglo-Soviet-American Coalition; Earl Browder, Make 1943 the Decisive Year; Earl Browder, Policy for Victory; Earl Browder, A Talk about the Communist Party; Earl Browder, A Talk about the Party; Earl Browder, Wage Policy in War Production; William Z. Foster, The People and the Congress; Sender Garlin, The Real Rickenbacker; Sender Garlin, The Truth about Reader's Digest; Roy Hudson, Communists and the Trade Unions; Jürgen Kuczynski, 300 Million Slaves and Serfs; A. Landy, Marxism and the Woman Question; Paul Merker, Whither Germany?; Robert Minor, Invitation to Join the Communist Party; Louise Mitchell, Food Prices and Rationing; George Morris, Planning for Victory; Frank Ryhlick, Congress and You; Mikhail Sholokhov, The Science of Hatred; Stages in the History of the Communist Party; Peter Wieden, This Is Our Enemy (Box-folder 148: 3)
        - Manual for Community Club Leaders; The President's Message to Congress; Morris U. Schappes, The Daily Worker, 1944 (Box-folder 148: 4)
        - James S. Allen, World Cooperation and Postwar Prosperity; Eugene Dennis, America at the Crossroads; Maurice Dobb, Marx as an Economist; William Z. Foster and Eugene Dennis, The Menace of American Imperialism, and America Needs the Communist Party; Sender Garlin, Enemies of the Peace; V. J. Jerome, The Treatment of Defeated Germany; Maxine Levi, The Communists and the Liberation of Europe; George Morris, Reconversion; Joseph North, What Are We Doing in China?; The Present Situation and the Next Tasks; Joseph Starobin, The San Francisco World Security Conference, 1945 (Box-folder 148: 5)
        - Samuel Adams: Selections from His Writings; James S. Allen, Who Owns America?; Eugene Dennis, The People against the Trusts; Eugene Dennis, The Red-Baiters Menace America; Eugene Dennis, The Un-Americanism of Hearst's John Sentinel; Eugene Dennis, What America Faces; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Meet the Communists; William Z. Foster, The Menace of a New World War; William Z. Foster, Our Country Needs a Strong Communist Party; William Z. Foster et al., Marxism-Leninism vs. Revisionism; Betty Gannett, The Communist Party and You; A Handbook for Club Officers, 1946 (Box-folder 148: 6)
        - A. B. Magil, Socialism; George Marion, The "Free Press"; Louise Mitchell, America's Housing Crisis; On the Struggle against Revisionism; Toward Singing Tomorrows: The Last Testament of Gabriel Péri; Herb Tank, Communists on the Waterfront, 1946 (Box-folder 148: 7)
        - Alexander Bittelman, Program for Survival; Peter V. Cacchione, Wall Street on the Warpath; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Woman's Place in the Fight for a Better World; William Z. Foster, The Meaning of the Nine-Party Communist Conference; William Z. Foster, The Need for Unity among the Maritime Workers; William Z. Foster, Organized Labor and the Fascist Danger; William Z. Foster, Workers, Defend Your Unions!; Donald Freeman, Tax Relief for Whom?; Robert Friedman, How's Your Health?; V. J. Jerome, A World "Christian Front"? and the Anti-Social Ethics of Red-Baiters; Al Lannon and Harry Mann, The Mystery of 1000 "Vanished" Ships; George Morris, The Red-Baiting Racket and How It Works; Nemmy Sparks, What Is Socialism?; Theory and Practice of the Communist Party; Alexander Trachtenberg, History of May Day; Max Weiss, What Price Profits?; What You Should Know about the Communists; Milton Wolff, Franco Spain, Menace to World Peace, 1947 (Box-folder 149: 1)
        - James S. Allen, Marshall Plan; Nathan Ausubel, Jewish Culture in America; Richard O. Boyer, If This Be Treason; Joseph Clark, What's Behind the Berlin Crisis; Constitution of the Communist Party; Leo Cooper, Universal Military Training; Eugene Dennis, "Dangerous Thoughts"; Eugene Dennis Indicts the Wall Street Conspirators; Eugene Dennis, The Fascist Danger and How to Combat It; Eugene Dennis, The Third Party and the 1948 Elections; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, The Twelve and You; For Peace, Freedom, Prosperity, Socialism; William Z. Foster, Beware of the War Danger!; William Z. Foster, Labor and the Marshall Plan; Lawrence Mahan, Who Are the Foreign Agents?; Betty Millard, Woman against Myth; Steve Murdock, The Man Behind the Warren Mask; Paul Richards, Spotlight on Germany; John L. Spivak, The "Save the Country" Racket; Joseph Starobin, Should Americans Back the Marshall Plan?; Olive Sutton, Murder Inc. in Greece; Maurice Thorez, What Next in France? (Box-folder 149: 2)
        - Marion Bachrach, The Federal Jury Is Stacked against You; George Blake, Who Pays for the Cold War?; Bernard Burton, A New Depression?; Abraham Chapman, The North Atlantic Pact; David Englestein and Carl Hirsch, A Tale of Two Workers; Howard Fast, Intellectuals in the Fight for Peace; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Labor's Own William Z. Foster; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Stoolpigeon; Rob Fowler Hall, The Record of Truman's 81st Congress; Maritime Workers at the Crossroads; George Morris, Where Is the CIO Going?, 1949 (Box-folder 149: 3)
        - The Big Plot; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, Fighters for Peace; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, The Plot to Gag America; For Peace, Jobs, Civil Rights, Security; Gus Hall, Hands Off Korea and Formosa; Rob Fowler Hall, FEPC; Alphaeus Hunton, Africa Fights for Freedom; Samuel Sillen, Cold War in the Classroom; Some Ideological Questions on the Struggle for Peace, 1950 (Box-folder 149: 4)
        - Joseph Clark, Who Wants War?; Eugene Dennis, The MacArthur Ouster; W. E. B. Du Bois, I Take My Stand for Peace; Carl Hirsch, Public Enemies in Public Office; A Manual on Self Study, 1951 (Box-folder 149: 5)
        - Bernard Burton, We Can Have Peace and Jobs!; The Case of Puerto Rico; Mel Fiske, McCarthyism in the Courts; Milton Howard, McCarthyism and the Big Lie; Mark Logan and Sam Douglas, The Anatomy of McCarthyism; Alex Parker, Organizing the Party for Victory over Reaction; Victor Perlo, Israel and Dollar Diplomacy; Andrew Stevens, New Opportunities in the Fight for Peace and Democracy, 1953 (Box-folder 149: 6)
        - The American Way to Jobs, Peace, Equal Rights and Democracy; Betty Gannett, The Communist Program; Joseph Morton, Depression, 1954 (Box-folder 149: 7)
        - Joseph Clark, Geneva; Adam Lapin, Coexistence or No Existence, 1955 (Box-folder 149: 8)
        - Declaration of Communist and Workers' Parties of Socialist Countries, 1957 (Box-folder 149: 9)
        - James S. Allen et al., Disarmament and the American Economy; Gus Hall, The Summit Failure, 1960 (Box-folder 149: 10)
        - James E. Jackson, The Meaning of Black Power, 1966 (Box-folder 149: 11)
        - Gus Hall, Toward a Peace Ticket in 1968, 1967 (Box-folder 149: 12)
        - Hyman Lumer, The Fight against Trotskyism, 1968 (Box-folder 149: 13)
        - Clara Coló n, Enter Fighting: Today's Woman; Emile Touma, About the Idea of a Palestinian State, 1970 (Box-folder 149: 14)
        - Gus Hall, A Lame Duck in Turbulent Waters, 1972 (Box-folder 149: 15)
      - Leaflets, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 149: 16)
    - Communist Party (Marxist-Leninist)
      - People's Voice. Vol. 3 no. 1-2, 4/5-7/8, (1967) (Box-folder 149: 17)
      - Leaflets, 1967 (Box-folder 149: 18)
    - Communist Party (Opposition) (Box 150)
      - Workers Age. Vol. 2 no. 22-23, vol. 3 no. 1-9, vol. 5 no. 30, vol. 6 no. 1, (1933) (1934) (1936) (1937) (Box-folder 150: 1)
      - Pamphlets. For Unity of the World Communist Movement; Will Herberg, The C.I.O., (1934) (1937) (Box-folder 150: 2)
    - Communist Political Association. Pamphlets. David Goldway, The Communist Political Association; Roy Hudson, Post-War Jobs for Veterans, Negroes, Women; Robert Minor, The Heritage of the Communist Political Association; Earl Browder, Why America Is Interested in the Chinese Communists; Eugene Dennis, The Elections and the Outlook for National Unity, (1944) (1944) (1944) (1945) (1945) (Box-folder 150: 3)
    - Communist Workers Group. Pamphlet. Soviet Union and War 1, (1939) (Box-folder 150: 4)
    - Correspondence Group
      - Correspondence. Vol. 1 no. 10, 14, 31, no. 8 [sic], vol. 8 no. 1, 4, (1954) (1955) (1964) (Box-folder 150: 5)
      - Pamphlets. Union Committeemen and Wildcat Strikes; Conrad J. Lynn, Monroe, North Carolina: Turning Point in American History, (ca. 1955) (1962) (Box-folder 150: 6)
    - Daniel De Leon League
      - The De Leonist. No. 1-2, no. 3-5, (1969) (1970) (Box-folder 150: 7)
      - Leaflets, 1969 (Box-folder 150: 8)
    - Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee
      - Internal circulated documents, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 150: 9)
      - Pamphlets. We Are Socialists of the Democratic Left; Michael Harrington, Capitalism, Socialism and Energy, (1973) (1974) (Box-folder 150: 10)
      - Leaflets, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 150: 11)
    - Emergency Civil Liberties Committee. Pamphlets. The Smith Act; For Abolition of the Inquisitorial Committees of Congress; The Watkins Decision of the United States Supreme Court; David Wesley, Hate Groups and the Un-American Activities Committee, (1956) (1957) (1957) (1961) (Box-folder 150: 12)
    - End Poverty League. Pamphlets. Upton Sinclair, EPIC Answers; Upton Sinclair, I, Governor of California; Upton Sinclair, Immediate EPIC; Upton Sinclair, The Lie Factory Starts 11; Upton Sinclair, We, People of America; James Martin, United Front or Fascism, (1934) (1934) >(1934) (1934) (1934) (1935) (Box-folder 150: 13)
    - Facing Reality Committee
      - Speak Out. No. 17-19, 21/22, vol. 2 no. 1-4, 7/8-9, no. 10, (1968) (1969) (1970) (Box-folder 150: 14)
      - Pamphlet. Paul Romano, Life in the Factory, (n.d.) (Box-folder 150: 15)
    - Farmer-Labor Party [Minnesota]
      - Pamphlets. Bread or Straw; Fascism; The Tax Problem of Farmers and Wage-Workers of Minnesota, (1934) (1934) (1934) (Box-folder 150: 16)
      - Leaflets, 1926-1944 (Box-folder 150: 17)
    - Federated Press. Labor's News. Vol. 20 no. 3, (1931) (Box-folder 150: 18)
    - Freedom and Peace Party [New York] (Box 151)
      - Free Press. No. 2-3, (1969) (Box-folder 151: 1)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 151: 2)
      - Leaflets, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 151: 3)
    - Freedom Socialist Party
      - Internal circulated documents, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 151: 4)
      - Pamphlets. Introducing the Freedom Socialist Party; Richard Kirk and Clara Kaye, Crisis and Leadership, (1967) (1969) (Box-folder 151: 5)
      - Leaflets, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 151: 6)
    - Friends of the Soviet Union. Pamphlets. A. A. Heller, The Decisive Year in the Soviet Union; Through Workers' Eyes; Corliss Lamont, On Understanding Soviet Russia; Who Are the Friends of the Soviet Union?; Why Soviet Russia Should Be Recognized; Corliss Lamont, The Story of Soviet Progress; The U.S.S.R. and Finland, (1931) (1931) (1933) (1933) (1933) (1938) (1939) (Box-folder 151: 7)
    - Independent Communist Labor League. Workers Age. Vol. 6 no. 33, vol. 7 no. 9-12, (1937) (1938) (Box-folder 151: 8)
    - Independent Labor League [first]. Workers Age. Vol. 7 no. 31, 33, vol. 8 no. 13, 36, (1938) (1939) (Box-folder 151: 9)
    - Independent Labor League [second]. The Sentinel. Vol. 5 no. 2, (1946) (Box-folder 151: 10)
    - Independent Socialist Clubs
      - Bulletin. No. 2, 5, (1969) (Box-folder 151: 11)
      - Independent Socialist. No. 3, no. 4, 5 supp., 6-7, no. 8-11, (1967) (1968) (1969) (Box-folder 151: 12)
      - Reports. No. 1, 3, (1969) (Box-folder 151: 13)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1968 (Box-folder 152: 1)
      - Pamphlets. Hal Draper, Independent Socialism; Hal Draper, The Two Souls of Socialism; Stanley Weir, A New Era of Labor Revolt; David Friedman et al., Crisis in the Schools, (1964) (1966) (1966) (1969) (Box-folder 152: 2)
      - Leaflets, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 152: 3)
    - Independent Socialist League
      - Forum
        - Vol. 1 no. 1, vol. 2 no. 3, n.n., (1949) (1950) (1951) (Box-folder 152: 4)
        - N.n., n.n., n.n., (1952) (1953) (1957) (Box-folder 152: 5)
      - Pamphlet. H. W. Benson, The Communist Party at the Crossroads, (1957) (Box-folder 152: 6)
    - Industrial Union League
      - Internal circulated documents, n.d. (Box-folder 152: 7)
      - Pamphlet. Walter H. Senior, The Bankruptcy of Reform, (1932) (Box-folder 152: 8)
    - Industrial Union Party
      - Industrial Unionist. Vol. 7 no. 11, (1939) (Box-folder 152: 9)
      - Pamphlets. Daniel De Leon, Reform or Revolution; Daniel De Leon, Socialist Reconstruction of Society; Daniel De Leon, What Means This Strike?; C.I.O.: Promise or Menace?, (1934) (1934) (1935) (1937) (Box-folder 152: 10)
    - Industrial Workers of the World
      - Industrial Worker. Vol. 74 no. 9-10, (1977) (Box-folder 152: 11)
      - Workers' Opposition. No. 1, (1973) (Box-folder 152: 12)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 152: 13)
      - Pamphlets. William E. Trautman, Direct Action and Sabotage; William E. Trautman, Industrial Unionism; Abner E. Woodruff, The Advancing Proletariat; Aleksandra Kollontai, The Workers Opposition in Russia; An Economic Interpretation of the Job; One Big Union of All the Workers; Unemployment and the Machine; One Big Union of the Industrial Workers of the World; Preamble and Constitution of the Industrial Workers of the World; The I.W.W.; The Story of the Sea, (1912) (1913) (1917) (1921) (1923) (1933) (1934) (1957) (1976) (n.d.) (n.d.) (Box-folder 152: 14)
      - Leaflets, 1945-1974 (Box-folder 152: 15)
    - International Labor Defense
      - Equal Justice. N.n., (1939) (Box-folder 152: 16)
      - Pamphlets. Free the Imperial Valley Prisoners; Walt Pickard, Burlington Dynamite Plot; Rose Baron, They Gave Their Freedom!; Mike Quin, The C.S. Case against Labor; Sasha Small, Ten Years of Labor Defense, (1932) (ca. 1934) (1935) (ca. 1935) (1935) (Box-folder 152: 17)
    - International League [Fourth International]. The Fourth International. No. 10, no. 13/14, (1975) (1976) (Box-folder 152: 18)
    - International Socialists (Box 153)
      - Bulletin
        - No. 1-3, (1970) (Box-folder 153: 1)
        - No. 4-6, 8-11, 14, (1971) (Box-folder 153: 2)
        - No. 17-18, 20-23, 28, 32-33, 35, (1972) (Box-folder 153: 3)
        - No. 36, (1973) (Box-folder 153: 4)
        - No. 54, (1975) (Box-folder 153: 5)
      - Bulletin of the Gay Caucus. No. 1, no. 2, (1970) (1971) (Box-folder 153: 6)
      - Forum
        - Vol. 3 no. 1, 3, (1969) (Box-folder 153: 7)
        - Vol. 3 no. 4, vol. 4 no. 1, (1970) (Box-folder 153: 8)
      - Industrial Bulletin. No. 1, (1975) (Box-folder 153: 9)
      - International Bulletin. No. 1, no. 3, (1972) (1973) (Box-folder 154: 1)
      - International Socialist. No. 19, (1970) (Box-folder 154: 2)
      - Labor Bulletin. No. 1, (1972) (Box-folder 154: 3)
      - National Report
        - No. 1-6, n.n., 10-15, 17, (1972) (Box-folder 154: 4)
        - No. 18, 20-21, (1973) (Box-folder 154: 5)
        - Vol. 3 no. 9-12, 16, 21-31, (1975) (Box-folder 154: 6)
      - Revolutionary Youth Organization Internal Bulletin. No. 1, (1975) (Box-folder 154: 7)
      - Special Convention Bulletin. No. 4, (n.d.) (Box-folder 154: 8)
      - Women's Bulletin. No. 5, (1970) (Box-folder 154: 9)
      - Women's Commission Bulletin. No. 1, (1973) (Box-folder 154: 10)
      - Minutes
        - 1970 (Box-folder 154: 11)
        - 1971 (Box-folder 154: 12)
        - 1973 (Box-folder 154: 13)
      - Internal circulated documents (Box 155)
        - 1969 (Box-folder 155: 1)
        - 1970 (Box-folder 155: 2-3)
        - 1971 (Box-folder 155: 4)
        - 1973 (Box-folder 155: 5)
        - 1975 (Box-folder 155: 6)
        - Undated (Box-folder 155: 7)
      - Pamphlets. Kim Moody, The American Working Class in Transition; Lori Larkin and Eric Langdon, Puerto Rican Independence; Lori Larkin, Productivity; Steve Zeluck, Toward Teacher Power; Laurie Landy, Women and the Chinese Revolution; Laurie Landy, Women in Capitalist Society; Ilene Winkler, Women Workers, (ca. 1969) (1972) (ca. 1973) (ca. 1973) (n.d.) (n.d.) (n.d.) (Box-folder 155: 8)
      - Leaflets, 1969-1976 (Box-folder 155: 9)
    - International Trotskyist Committee. International Trotskyist Review. No. 1, (1985) (Box-folder 155: 10)
    - International Workers Order. Pamphlets. Why Every Worker Should Join the International Workers Order; Herbert Benjamin, A Program for Peace and Recovery, (1932) (1940) (Box-folder 155: 11)
    - International Workers Party (Box 156)
      - Critical Practice. No. 2, (1975) (Box-folder 156: 1)
      - The Struggle. Vol. 2 no. 3, vol. 3 no. 2, (1977) (1978) (Box-folder 156: 2)
      - Pamphlet. Fred Newman, A Manifesto on Method, (1974) (Box-folder 156: 3)
      - Leaflets and press coverage, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 156: 4)
    - Internationalist Workers Party
      - El bolchevique. No. 15, no. 16-18, no. 20-22, no. 24, (1981) (1982) (1983) (1984) (Box-folder 156: 5)
      - Trotskyist Correspondence. No. 1, (1983) (Box-folder 156: 6)
      - Working Class Opposition. No. 1-3, no. 4-6, (1982) (1983) (Box-folder 156: 7)
    - Johnson-Forest Tendency. Pamphlet. C. L. R. James et al., The Invading Socialist Society, (1947) (Box-folder 156: 8)
    - Labor Party League
      - The Worker. No. 1-2, (1975) (Box-folder 156: 9)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1975 (Box-folder 156: 10)
      - Leaflet, 1975 (Box-folder 156: 11)
    - Labor Research Associates. Pamphlets. Vern Smith, The Frame-Up System; Alexander Trachtenberg, The Heritage of Gene Debs; Elliot E. Cohen, The Yellow Dog Contract; Robert L. Cruden, The End of the Ford Myth; Robert W. Dunn, Spying on Workers; Anna Rochester, Wall Street; Grace Hutchins, Children under Capitalism; Harvey O'Connor, How Mellon Got Rich; Anna Louise Strong, Dictatorship and Democracy in the Soviet Union; William O. Thompson and Mary Van Kleeck, NRA from Within; Robert W. Dunn, Company Unions Today; Hy Kravif, Tel and Tel; Wages and Profits in Wartime, (1930) (1930) (1932) (1932) (1932) (1932) (1933) (1933) (1934) (1934) (1935) (1935) (1941) (Box-folder 156: 12)
    - League for a Revolutionary Workers' Party
      - Labor Front. Vol. 5 no. 7, (1938) (Box-folder 156: 13)
      - New International Bulletin. No. 1, (1935) (Box-folder 156: 14)
      - Internal circulated documents, 1934-1937 (Box-folder 156: 15)
      - Pamphlets. B. J. Field, Prospects of American Capitalism; Trotskyism, (ca. 1934) (1940) (Box-folder 156: 16)
      - Leaflets, n.d. (Box-folder 156: 17)
    - League for Industrial Democracy (Box 157)
      - Pamphlets
        - Stuart Chase, The Challenge of Waste; Harry W. Laidler, How America Lives; Harry W. Laidler, Roads to Freedom; Stuart Chase, One Billion Wild Horses; Fascism; Miles, Socialism's New Beginning; Maurice Goldbloom et al., Strikes under the New Deal, (1922) (1924) (1925) (1930) (1934) (1934) (ca. 1935) (Box-folder 157: 1)